Register of the Baronessa Marii͡a Dmitrievna Vrangel' collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Part I (Boxes 2-38)
  - File 8, 1928-1937 (Boxes 13-15)
    - Cossacks
      - Correspondence, including biographical material and memoirs
        - Orlov, A., handwritten memoirs, "Put' flotilii Admirala Starka", and "Sredi peskov Mesopotamii", November 1931-January 1932, September 1930 (Box 14, Folder 21)
        - Pavlichenko, Maj.-Gen. I., clippings re Kuban Cossacks in South America, November 1933 (Box 14, Folder 22)
        - Persianov, D., February 1933 (Box 14, Folder 23)
        - Popovko, Col. F., undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
        - SHilzhikov, Maj.-Gen. I., typescript, May 1933 (Box 14, Folder 25)
        - SHutenbakh, Capt. G. von, includes description of Kuban Cossacks abroad, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
        - Skachkov, P., September 1932 (Box 14, Folder 27)
        - Skvortsov, Maj.-Gen. M., undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
        - Svatikov, S., 1932 (Box 14, Folder 29)
        - Zborovskii, Maj.-Gen. V., also includes biographical information re Col. K. Zershchikov, Col. A. Rogozhin and Voiskovoi Starshina N. Galushkin, June 1932-January 1940 (Box 14, Folder 30)
        - Zershchikov, Col. K., includes essay on Kuban and Terek Cossacks in Czechoslovakia, May 1929-July 1938 (Box 14, Folder 31)
        - ZHevich, P., February 1933 (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - General
        - "4-yi Donskoi Kazachii Polk ", handwritten, October 1930, 1920-1930 (Box 14, Folder 33)
        - "Dannyia o zaniatii russkikh zemledel'tsev v CHekhoslovatskoi Respubliki...1932...", typescript, August 1932 (Box 14, Folder 34)
        - "Kubanets, informatsionnyi listok...", typescript, July 1928 (Box 14, Folder 35)
        - List of cossack organizations abroad, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
        - "Svodno-Kubanskii Polk", list of graduates of military courses, typescript, September 1932 (Box 14, Folder 37)
        - "Territorial'nyia i natsional'nyia ob"edineniia", printed excerpt, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 38)
      - Printed matter
        - Eniseiskii Kazak, May 1933 (Box 14, Folder 39)
        - Irkutskii Kazak, April-May 1934, April-May 1935 (Box 14, Folder 40)
        - "Kazachestvo i kommunisty", Kazach'e ob"edinenie dlia bor'by za rodinu, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 41)
        - Kazachii Nabat, June 1933-January 1934 (Box 14, Folder 42)
        - Kazaki zagranitsei, December 1927-March 1935 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
        - Kazach'e Edinstvo, March 1934 (Box 15)
        - "Kratkaia Svodka Svedenii o ZHizni Kubanskikh Kazakov", January 1931 (Box 15, Folder 4)
        - "Kubantsy za rubezhom", excerpt, Al'manakh Russkoi Emigratsii, 1920-1930 (Box 15, Folder 5)
        - Orenburgskii Kazak, May 1933 (Box 15, Folder 6)
        - Rossiia i Kazachestvo, ZHurnal Vostochnago Kazach'iago Soiuza, September 1933-March 1935 (Box 15, Folder 7)
        - S. ZHarov i Donskoi Kazachii KHor, Berlin, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 8)
          Available on microfilm reel 17
        - S ibirskii Kazak, Harbin, December 1930, December 1933 (Box 15, Folder 9)
        - Clippings, includes material re cossacks in Peru, 1926-1935 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - File 9, 1920-1931 (Box 15)
    Russian aviation and aviators, especially I. Sikorsky. Includes correspondence and printed matter.
    - Aviation
      - Correspondence, including biographical material
        - Finne, K., August 1930 (Box 15, Folder 11)
        - Gikachev, V., January 1929 (Box 15, Folder 12)
        - Sikorskaia, E., June 1930 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Printed matter
        - CH asovoi, A viatsionnyi Nomer, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 14)
        - N asha Stikhiia, Simferopol', includes short story by Teffi, August 1920 (Box 15, Folder 15)
        - Finne, K., R usskie Vozdushnye Bogatyri I.I. Sikorskago, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Clippings and brochures
        - General, including V. Ivanov, V. Utgoff, M. Krygin and D. Riabushinskii, 1929-1934 (Box 16, Folder 1)
        - Sikorsky, I. and his company, 1928-1931 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - File 10, 1924-1932 (Boxes 16-17)
    Russian academics abroad. Includes correspondence, biographies, autobiographies and printed matter.
    - Russian academics abroad
      - List of photographs, handwritten, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, including biographical material
        - Abakumov, N., November 1931 (Box 16, Folder 4)
        - Aleksinskii, N., July 1931-November 1933 (Box 16, Folder 5)
        - Anichkov, E., September 1931 (Box 16, Folder 6)
        - Antsyferov, A., July, 1931 (Box 16, Folder 7)
        - Arsen'ev, N., undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
        - Baldin, S., May 1930-March 1933 (Box 16, Folder 9)
        - Bazanov, I., January 1932 (Box 16, Folder 10)
        - Beliaev, N., April 1932 (Box 16, Folder 11)
        - Berzin, R., April 1932 (Box 16, Folder 12)
        - Bilimovich, A., December 1930 (Box 16, Folder 13)
        - Boldyrev, A., October 1931 (Box 16, Folder 14)
        - Boldyrev, V. and E., August 1931 (Box 16, Folder 15)
        - Borodin, N., September 1931 (Box 16, Folder 16)
        - Brandt, A., October 1932 (Box 16, Folder 17)
        - CHubinskii, M., 1930-October 1931 (Box 16, Folder 18)
        - Davats, V., June 1929-November 1935 (Box 16, Folder 19)
        - Deisha, A., 1931 (Box 16, Folder 20)
        - Dobrovol'skaia-Zavadskaia, N., February 1932 (Box 16, Folder 21)
        - Elachich, A., June 1932 (Box 16, Folder 22)
        - Emanuilova, A., June, 1931 (Box 16, Folder 23)
        - Finisov, P., April 1933 (Box 16, Folder 24)
        - Forst, D., November 1931-March 1932 (Box 16, Folder 25)
        - Geish, A., undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
        - Genzel (Haensel), P., January 1932 (Box 16, Folder 27)
        - Gins, G., May 1931 (Box 16, Folder 28)
        - Glubokovskii, N., July, 1931 (Box 16, Folder 29)
        - Grimm, D., September 1924-December 1931 (Box 16, Folder 30)
        - Grimm, I., September-October 1931 (Box 16, Folder 31)
        - IAkovlev, D., January-March 1933 (Box 16, Folder 32)
        - Il'in, I., 1929-1931. Includes brochure, IAd Bol'shevizma and clippings (Box 16, Folder 33)
          Available on microfilm reel 18
        - Karapetov, V., June 1927 (Box 16, Folder 34)
        - Karpovich, M., July, 1931 (Box 16, Folder 35)
        - Kepinov, L., June 1931 (Box 16, Folder 36)
        - Kizivetter, A., undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
        - Kopylov, A., November 1931 (Box 16, Folder 38)
        - Korzukhin, I., June, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 39)
        - Kovalevskii, P., undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
        - Konovalov, S., October 1931 (Box 16, Folder 41)
        - Korenchevskii, V., includes appeals and pamphlets re scientific and social work, 1929-1931 (Box 16, Folder 42)
        - Korsakov, F., February 1932 (Box 16, Folder 43)
        - Koshkin, S., May-August 1931 (Box 16, Folder 44)
        - Krylov, D., February 1932 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Kul'man, N., January 1930-January 1932. Includes pamphlet, Russkaia KHudozhestvennaia Literatura za Rubezhom i v Sovetskoi Rossii, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 2)
        - Lakota, T., October 1930 (Box 17, Folder 3)
        - Lappo, I., October 1934 (Box 17, Folder 4)
        - Lepeshkin, V., July, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 5)
        - Makletsov, A., August 1931-1932 (Box 17, Folder 6)
        - Melkikh, A., June, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 7)
        - Metal'nikov, S., June-July 1931 (Box 17, Folder 8)
        - Miliukov, P., undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
        - Misheev, N., April 1930 (Box 17, Folder 10)
        - Mitinskii, A., April-August 1931 (Box 17, Folder 11)
        - Monakhov, P, July, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 12)
        - Nikitin, V., 1933 (Box 17, Folder 13)
        - Nol'de, B., July 1931 (Box 17, Folder 14)
        - Novikov, M., undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
        - Onou, A., December 1931 (Box 17, Folder 16)
        - Pletnev, V., October-November 1934 (Box 17, Folder 17)
        - Pogodin, A., May 1931 (Box 17, Folder 18)
        - Popov, N., April 1932 (Box 17, Folder 19)
        - Preobrazhenskii, N., December 1931 (Box 17, Folder 20)
        - Petrunkevich, A., July, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 21)
        - Riabushinskii, D. (includes letters of IU. Karmalina), April 1930 (Box 17, Folder 22)
        - Rostovtsev, M., Seminarium Kondakovianum, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 23)
        - Ruzskii, D., October 1931 (Box 17, Folder 24)
        - Sakhanev, V., 1934 (Box 17, Folder 25)
        - Saltykov, S., undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
        - Satina, S., March 1930-June, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 27)
        - Savin, S., April 1932 (Box 17, Folder 28)
        - SHakhmatov, M., undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
        - SHcherbakov, A., undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
        - Sokol'tsov, D., March 1935 (Box 17, Folder 31)
        - Sorokin, P., June, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 32)
        - Spektorskii, E., April 1931-September 1932 (Box 17, Folder 33)
        - Stebut, A., November 1932 (Box 17, Folder 34)
        - Struve, P. (includes letters of N. Struve), April, 1928-April 1932 (Box 17, Folder 35)
        - Taranovskii, F., February 1931 (Box 17, Folder 36)
        - Timoshenko, S., August 1929-July 1931 (Box 17, Folder 37)
        - Tiutriumov, I., August 1932 (Box 17, Folder 38)
        - Troitskii, S., July 1931 (Box 17, Folder 39)
        - TSebrikova, L., December 1931 (Box 17, Folder 40)
        - Vacquier, T., October 1931 (Box 17, Folder 41)
        - Varsher, T., undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
        - Verbitskii, F., October 1932 (Box 17, Folder 43)
        - Vernadsky, G., May, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 44)
        - Vinogradskii, S., undated (Box 17, Folder 45)
        - Volkonskii, Prince M., December 1931 (Box 17, Folder 46)
        - Vrangel', Baron N., August 1932 (Box 17, Folder 47)
        - Zavadskii, S., February-March 1932 (Box 17, Folder 48)
        - Zernov, N., typescript report, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 49)
        - Zernov, V., July 1931 (Box 17, Folder 50)
        - Zvorykin, V., undated (Box 17, Folder 51)
      - General
        - Melkikh, A., "Russkii Akademicheskii Soiuz v Germanii", also includes statutes, typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 52)
        - Monakhov, P., "Kratkii ocherk deiatel'nosti Russkoi Akademicheskoi Gruppy v Konstantinopole, ", handwritten, 1921-1926 (Box 17, Folder 53)
        - "Ustav Soiuza Russkikh Akademicheskikh Organizatsii za Granitsei..." (Box 17, Folder 54)
        - Lists of professors: University of Latvia, U.S., Prague, young Russian academics abroad. Handwritten, typescript and printed matter, 1930-1931 (Box 17, Folder 55)
      - Clippings, 1926-1931 (Box 17, Folder 56)
        Available on microfilm reel 19
  - File 11, 1925-1932 (Box 18)
    Russian academic groups. Miscellaneous material.
    - Russian academic groups abroad
      - Regional groups, miscellaneous material
        - Belgium, handwritten, July, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 1)
        - Bulgaria, handwritten, March 1931 (Box 18, Folder 2)
        - China, Harbin, Law Faculty, printed copy, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - Czechoslovakia
          - General, typescript, July 1931 (Box 18, Folder 4)
          - "Seminarii Imeni N.P. Kondakova v Prage", miscellaneous material, 1925-1930 (Box 18, Folder 5)
        - Estonia, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 6)
        - Finland, handwritten and typescript, March 1932 (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - France, typescript, November 1927-1930 (Box 18, Folder 8)
        - Germany, "Russkii Nauchnyi Institut v Berline", printed brochures and course listings, 1923-1931 (Box 18, Folder 9)
        - Great Britain, typescript and handwritten, 1925-1930 (Box 18, Folder 10)
        - IUgoslavia, "Russkii Institut v Belgrade", includes letter of E. Spektorskii, 1928-1931 (Box 18, Folder 11)
        - U.S., typescript, December 1930-1931 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - General
        - Mater'ialy dlia bibliografii russkikh nauchnykh trudov za rubezhom. 1920-1930, Belgrad, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 13)
        - Russkie Akademicheskie Organizatsii Zagranitsei
          - CHetvertyi S"ezd...v Belgrade, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 14)
          - Russkii Pedagogicheskii S"ezd v Prage v List of participants, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 15)
          - S"ezdy Russkikh Akademicheskikh Organizatsii Zagranitsei, Prague, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 16)
        - Clippings, miscellaneous, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 17)
          Available on microfilm reel 20
  - File 12, 1922-1933 (Boxes 18-19)
    Russian students and student organizations. Miscellaneous material.
    - Russian students and student organizations
      - International aid organizations for Russian students abroad, typescript and printed reports, 1922-1932 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Soiuz Ob"edinenii Russkikh Okonchivshikh vysshiia Uchebnyia Zavedeniia, miscellaneous typescript and handwritten material, 1931-1933 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Czechoslovakia, O.R.E.S.O. miscellaneous material, typescript and printed matter, 1929-1932 (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Estonia, "Obshchestvo Russkikh Studentov", 1930 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - U.S., Russian Student's Fund, typescript, 1928 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Clippings, 1930-1931 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - File 13, 1928-1943 (Boxes 19-20)
    Individuals active in social organizations and community affairs. Includes correspondence, biographies, autobiographies and printed matter. Also includes some correspondence from File 35
    - Individuals active in social organizations and community affairs
      - Correspondence, includes biographical material and memoirs
        - Argunov, A., undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - Arshaulov, V., October 1931-August 1932 (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - Astrov, N., August 1930-September 1932 (Box 19, Folder 6)
        - Bakhrushin, M., 1928-1931 (Box 19, Folder 7)
        - Bobrinskoy, Count A., clipping, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 8)
        - Brasol, Boris, includes printed matter, November 1931 (Box 19, Folder 9)
        - Bulgakov, V., September-December 1934 (Box 19, Folder 10)
        - CHebyshev, N., March 1933 (Box 19, Folder 11)
        - Dmitriev, N., February 1932 (Box 19, Folder 12)
        - Fel'dman, L., August 1931 (Box 19, Folder 13)
        - Glinka, G., May 1932 (Box 19, Folder 14)
        - Gorlov, V., January 1932 (Box 19, Folder 15)
        - Gorodetskii, S., June 1932 (Box 19, Folder 16)
        - Ikonnikov, N., includes memoir of Civil War, September 1932 (Box 19, Folder 17)
        - Iznar, N., September 1931-November 1932 (Box 19, Folder 18)
        - Karrik, V., December 1933-July 1934 (Box 19, Folder 19)
        - Karinskii, N., August 1932 (Box 19, Folder 20)
        - KHripunov, A., October 1931 (Box 19, Folder 21)
        - Kindiakov, M., October 1931 (Box 19, Folder 22)
        - Kolokol'nikov, V., undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
        - Kovalevskii, E. and Kovalevskaia, I., 1925-March 1936 (Box 19, Folder 24)
        - Maklakov, V., October 1928-1932 (Box 19, Folder 25)
        - Markozov, V., February 1932 (Box 19, Folder 26)
          Available on microfilm reel 21
        - Mel'nikov, A., December 1931-January 1932 (Box 19, Folder 27)
        - Mosolov, A., September-November 1933 (Box 19, Folder 28)
        - Naumov, A., December 1936 (Box 19, Folder 29)
        - Olsufiev, Graf D., September 1931-February 1932 (Box 19, Folder 30)
        - Ol'denburgskii, Prince A., clipping, includes description of Narodnyi Dom in Petersburg, December 1933 (Box 19, Folder 31)
        - Paleolog, S., includes material re "Bratstvo Russkoi Pravdy", February 1930-March 1933 (Box 19, Folder 32)
        - Repninskii, IA., January 1932 (Box 19, Folder 33)
        - Riabushinskii, V., June 1931 (Box 19, Folder 34)
        - Sablin, E., April 1932 (Box 19, Folder 35)
        - SHneider, I., May 1933 (Box 19, Folder 36)
        - SHul'gin, V., includes autobiography, April 1932-January 1933 (Box 19, Folder 37)
        - SHuvalova, A., August-October 1931 (Box 19, Folder 38)
        - Smolianinov, V., February 1935 (Box 19, Folder 39)
        - Stolbetsova, (?), memoirs of WW I nurse, January 1933 (Box 19, Folder 40)
        - Sviatopolk-Mirskaia, Princess M., includes memoir of evacuation, June 1932 (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Tenishev, Prince V., April 1932 (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - TSurikov, N., April-August 1931 (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - Tubental', V., (V. SHmidt), 1934 (Box 20, Folder 4)
        - Tyrkova-Williams, A., January 1932 (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - Voinovskii-Kriger, E., August 1931 (Box 20, Folder 6)
        - Voitsekhovskii, S., July 1931 (Box 20, Folder 7)
        - Witte, G. von, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
        - ZHekulina, A., September 1930-November 1943 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - File 14, 1921-1930 (Box 20)
    Russian finance and trade organizations. Miscellaneous material.
    - Russian finance and trade associations (Box 20)
      - Rossiiskii Torgovo-Promyshlennyi i Finansovyi Soiuz v Parizhe
        - Yearly reports, typescript, 1924-1929 (Box 20, Folder 10)
        - Reports and memorandum, typescript, 1928-1930 (Box 20, Folder 11)
        - Printed matter (Box 20)
          - Brochures, 1921-1922 (Box 20, Folder 12)
          - Clippings, includes Petrogradskii Mezhdunarodnyi Bank, 1930 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - File 15, 1928-1934 (Boxes 20-21)
    Russian engineers, scientists and inventors. Miscellaneous material.
    - Russian engineers, scientists and inventors
      - General, typescript biographies and clippings, 1928-1935 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - "Biulleten'", Federatsiia Soiuzov Russkikh Inzhenerov Zagranitsei, typescript, 1928-1930 (Box 20, Folder 15-16)
        Available on microfilm reels 21-22
      - Inzhener, Vestnik Soiuza Russkikh Inzhenerov v Korolevstve S.KH.S., printed matter, 1923-1929 (Box 21, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 22
      - Reports re Russian engineers, typescript
        - Belgium, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 2)
        - Czechoslovakia, miscellaneous, including speech of Gen. Hermonius, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
        - Danzig, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
        - France, includes letter of N. Iznarts, projects of P. Monakhov and miscellaneous material re "Ob"edinenyi Komitet Inzhenernykh i Tekhnicheskikh Organizatsii v Parizhe", handwritten and typescript, 1932-1934 (Box 21, Folder 5)
        - Greece, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Clippings, 1929-1930 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - File 16, 1923-1935 (Boxes 21-22)
    Russian legal, medical and educational organizations. Includes correspondence, memoirs, biographies and printed matter.
    - Russian legal organizations
      - Ob"edinenie Russkikh Advokatov vo Frantsii, Union des avocats russes en France, printed copy, 1928-1935 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Ob"edinenie Russkikh IUristov v Prage, typescript bulletin, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Soiuz Russkoi Prisiazhnoi Advokatury v Germanii, Russkaia advokatura v Germanii. Otchet o deiatel'nosti Soiuza za 10 let (1920-1930), printed copy (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Soiuz Russkoi Prisiazhnoi Advokatury v S.SH.A., printed copy, 1926 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Zarubezhnyi Soiuz Russkikh Sudebnykh Deiatelei, Belgrade, typescript and printed matter, also includes curriculum vitae and miscellaneous material re Senator S. Tregubov, 1929-1932 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - Clippings, 1930-1931 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Russian medical doctors
      - Correspondence, includes biographical material and memoirs re zemstvo, WWI and emigration, typescript and handwritten
        - General, 1930-1935 (Box 21, Folder 14)
        - CHarnetskaia, A., 1923 (Box 21, Folder 15)
        - Sergievskii, P., 1935 (Box 21, Folder 16)
        - ZHukov, S., 1931-1934 (Box 21, Folder 17)
          Available on microfilm reel 23
      - Clippings, 1931-1934
    - Russian medical associations
      - Obshchestvo Russkikh Vrachei Imeni Mechnikova vo Frantsii, handwritten, typescript and printed matter, 1930-1931 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Obshchestvo Russkikh Vrachei v CH.S.R., typescript report, "Komitet po bor'be s tuberkulezom", 1932 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Russian Medical Association in Great Britain, January 1929 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Soiuz Russkikh Vrachei Zagranitsei, typescript report re congress in Prague, May 1928 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Soiuz Russkikh Vrachei v Germanii, typescript report, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Rossiiskoe Obshchestvo Krasnago Kresta (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
        - General. Miscellaneous material, including correspondence and printed matter, relates mostly to Great Britain, France and Germany, 1923-1932
        - Komitet Popecheniia o Sestrakh Miloserdiia, 1929-1931 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Russian educational organizations
      - Obshchestvo Russkikh Pedagogov v Bolgarii, typescript report, November 1931 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Ob"edinenie Russkikh Uchitel'skikh Organizatsii Zagranitsei, Russkii Uchitel' v Emigratsii, printed copy, Prague, 1926 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Pedagogicheskoe Biuro po delam srednei i nisshei shkoly zagranitsei, miscellaneous typescript and printed matter, 1924-1931 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Pedagogicheskii S"ezd v Parizhe, clippings, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Soiuz Russkikh Pedagogov v Korolevstve S.KH.S., typescript bulletins and clippings, 1928-1932 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - File 17, 1920-1935 (Boxes 22-23)
    Russian educational institutions, including elementary and secondary education and military academies. Miscellaneous material.
    - Russian educational institutions
      - Bulgaria
        - Anglo-Russian Gymnasium, typescript report, 1935 (Box 22, Folder 14)
          Available on microfilm reel 24
        - Russkaia Gimnaziia-Internat "Moia Malen'kaia Rossiia", A. Dekhterev, June 1932-February 1933 (Box 22, Folder 15)
        - SHkola V.P. Kuzminoi, Sophia, miscelaneous typescript and handwritten material, also photographs, 1929-1932 (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Czechoslovakia. Gimnaziia v Moravskoi Trzhbove, yearly reports and other printed matter, 1926-1930 (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - China, Harbin, "Russkii Dom", miscellaneous material, handwritten, typescript and printed matter, 1923-1932 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Finland, typescript report, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - France (Box 23)
        - Russkaia Sredniaia SHkola v Parizhe and "Nina Brunelli Russian Girl's Home", correspondence with M. Maklakova and E. Kovalevskii, typescript and printed reports and brochures, 1928-1932 (Box 23, Folder 3)
        - Verr'erskoe Obshchezhitie dlia Russkikh Mal'chikov, letter of Gen. K. Sychev and photograph album, August 1933 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Germany. Deutsch-Russische St. Georgs-Schule, miscellaneous material, 1927-1931 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Greece. Russkaia Gimnaziia Zemsko-Gorodskogo Komiteta v Afinakh, typescript report, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Latvia. Orphanage and school in Riga, typescript report, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Lithuania. Printed matter, 1927-1928 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Poland. List of schools, typescript, 1927 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Yugoslavia. Includes Rusko-Srpska Zhenska Gimnazija, Russko-Serbskaia Gimnaziia, Belgrade and other handwritten, typescript and printed matter, 1930-1931 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - General
        - Rossiiskii Zemsko-Gorodskoi Komitet Pomoshchi Rossiiskim Grazhdanam Zagranitsei, Zarubezhnaia Russkaia SHkola, 1920-1924, printed copy (Box 23, Folder 11)
        - Rudenev, V., Sud'by Emigrantskoi SHkoly, printed copy, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, also includes camps and other social organizations, 1932-1935 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - File 18, 1920-1935 (Boxes 23-24)
    - Russian educational institutions
      - Military Academies (Kadetskie Korpusa)
        - Donskoi Imperatora Aleksandra III Kadetskii Korpus, handwritten report, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 14)
        - Krymskii Kadetskii Korpus, printed copy, 1922-1929 (Box 23, Folder 15)